James M. Hill Papers
© 2004 University of Connecticut
James M. Hill Papers.
1831-1888.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Hill, James M.
.75 linear feet.
The James M. Hill Papers consist primarily of the business records of Mr. Hill's store in North Madison, Connecticut.
MSS19960011
Biography
James M. Hill ( 1809-1889 ) owned a store in North Madison, Connecticut. He was also a constable.
Scope and Content
The James M. Hill Papers consist primarily of the business records of his store in North Madison, Connecticut. The records include account books and business ledgers. Nine account books cover the period 1832-1842, one business ledger tracks accounts by names of customers, and a second lists alcoholic beverages sold. The papers also contain an account book for the schooner "Baltic," a mathematics workbook, bills and receipts, legal papers documenting Hill's work as a constable, and miscellaneous papers including tax and donation lists.
Organization
Series I: Store Financial Records ( 1832-1844 ) include account books and business ledgers. Nine account books cover the period 1832-42, one business ledger tracks accounts by names of customers, and a second lists alcoholic beverages sold.
Series II: Financial Records ( undated, 1831-1886 ) contains an account book for the schooner "Baltic," and various bills and receipts.
Series III: Personal and Legal Papers ( undated, 1836-1888 ) contains a mathematics workbook, legal papers documenting Hill's work as a constable, and other papers including tax and donation lists.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to Connecticut history and business records, see especially the Account Books Collection. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Hill, James M.
Places:
North Madison, Conn.
Subjects:
Document Types:
Financial Records.; Legal Records.
Occupations:
Constable.; Merchant.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The papers were purchased from Cedric Robinson Booksellers in August 1996.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Store Financial Records, 1832-1844
  - Day Book, 1832-1834 (Box 1:1)
  - Day Book, 1834-1835 (Box 1:2)
  - Day Book, 1835 March - June (Box 1:3)
  - Day Book (Liquor only), 1835 March - September (Box 1:4)
  - Day Book, 1835-1836 (Box 1:5)
  - Day Book, 1836 January - June (Box 1:6)
  - Day Book, 1836-1838 (Box 1:7)
  - Day Book, 1839-1840 (Box 1:8)
  - Day Book, 1840-1842 (Box 1:9)
  - Ledger, 1836-1844 (Box 1:10)
  - Ledger (Liquor sales), 1835-1837 (Box 2:11)
- Series II: Financial Records, undated, 1831-1886
  - Account book for the schooner "Baltic", 1831-1832 (Box 2:12)
  - Bills and receipts, undated, 1835-1886 (Box 2:13)
- Series III: Personal and Legal Papers, undated, 1836-1888
  - Legal papers, 1836-1868 (Box 2:14)
  - Mathematics workbook, undated (Box 2:15)
  - Papers, undated, 1853-1888 (Box 2:16)